Guide to the Goddard-Riverside Community Center Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Goddard-Riverside Community Center Records,
1854-1994
Goddard-Riverside Community Center.
51 linear ft. (in 111 boxes & flat boxes).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4079917
History
Social settlement founded in 1959 through the merger of Riverside Community House and Goddard Neighborhood Center. Located on the upper West Side of Manhattan, the settlement provides such community services as day care, Head Start, athletics, college readiness programs, and a senior citizen center.
Scope and Content
The records include annual reports, board minutes, budgets, by-laws, correspondence, memos, publications, reports, scrapbooks, photographs and printed material. They document the settlement and its antecedent institutions from 1854 to 1994, offering a unique view of the first wave of the settlement house movement in America, as well as related philanthropy and social welfare activities in New York City over a 140 year period. The origins of Goddard-Riverside Community Center are documented in Series I, which includes eight institutional subseries. These records provide a wealth of information on philanthropic, social welfare and settlement work from the mid-19th century through the 1950s. Series II - IV document the activities of the settlement from 1959 to the 1990s, with a particular emphasis on the urban renewal period of the 1960s. Items in Series VII include photographs of staff, activities, facilities of Goddard-Riverside Community Center, as well as several of its predecessor institutions.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 7 series:
Series I: Predecessor Organizations
Series II: Administration
Series III: Board of Directors
Series IV: Executive Director Files, 1960-1994
Series V: Stephen Russo Files
Series VI: Programs and Activities
Series VII: Audio-Visual Material
Subjects
Child Study Association of America.; Friendly Aid Society (New York, N.Y.).; Goddard Neighborhood Center (New York, N.Y.).; Riverside Community House (New York, N.Y.).; Riverside Day Nursery (New York, N.Y.).; United Neighborhood Houses of New York, Inc. (New York, N.Y.).; Wel-Met, Inc. (New York, N.Y.).; Wilson Industrial School for Girls (New York, N.Y.).; New York (N.Y.)--History.; New York (N.Y.)--Social Conditions.; Community centers--New York (N.Y.).; Human services--New York (N.Y.).; Immigrants--New York (N.Y.).; Public housing--New York (N.Y.).; Social service--New York (N.Y.).; Social settlements--New York (N.Y.).; Social work--New York (N.Y.).; Urban renewal--New York (N.Y.).; Welfare--New York (N.Y.).; Administrative records; Annual reports.; Audio tapes.; Brochures.; Budgets.; Bylaws.; Case files.; Certificates.; Contracts.; Charters.; Deeds.; Financial records.; Fliers (printed matter).; Inventories.; Ledgers (account books).; Lists.; Manuals.; Memorandums.; Minutes.; Negatives.; Petitions.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Proposals.; Reports.; Rosters.; Scrapbooks.; Slides (photographs).; Speeches.; Wills.; Child welfare workers.; Social workers.; Women social workers.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Boxes 106-109 contain program records with client information of a confidential nature and are closed to researchers, with the exception of Goddard-Riverside Community Center staff, board members, or their approved agents, until 2060. All other records are open to research use without restrictions.
Acquisition
01/23/1995 M-95-01-23 Records GRCC Gift
Gift of the Goddard-Riverside Community Center, 1995.
- Series I: Predecessor Organizations
  - Subseries I.1: Wilson Industrial School for Girls
    - Annual Reports, 1862, 1870-72 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1873, 1875-77 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Annual Reports, 1878-81 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Annual Reports, 1882-85 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports, 1886-87, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Annual Reports, 1895, 1902, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Annual Reports, 1908-11 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Annual Reports, 1912, 1914, 1916, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Annual Reports, 1919-21, 1927-28, 1929-30 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Annual Reports, 1937-40 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Board of Directors: Correspondence, 1889, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Board of Directors. Correspondence, 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Board of Directors: Correspondence, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Board of Directors: Correspondence, 1953-54 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Board of Directors.: Executive Committee Minutes, 1855-61, 1891 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1855-67, (Bound Volume, ) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1877-81, (Bound Volume, ) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1941-54 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Brochure, ca. 1900 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - By-Laws, 1898-1902 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Certificate of Change of Purpose, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Certificate of Incorporation, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Contributions, 1920-23 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Contributions Journal, 1947-48, (Bound Volume, ) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - History, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - "Manual of the Wilson Mission Church,", ca. 1868 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - One Hundredth Anniversary and Merger, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Petition For Common School Funds, ca. 1862 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Real Estate, 1859-71 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Real Estate, 1872-95 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Real Estate-"Abstract of Title...,", 1880 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Real Estate-Deeds, 1860-75 (Box 298, Folder 1)
    - Real Estate-"Inspection Survey,", 1949 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Real Estate-"Report of Interview with Robert M. Davis,", ca. 1950 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Subscriptions and Donations, 1906-16, (Bound Volume, ) (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Wills and Bequests, 1895-1931 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Wills and Bequests-Stock Certificates, 1868-71 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "Woman's Industrial Exhibition,", 1912 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "Year Book of Woods Memorial Chapel,", 1898 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor of the Woods Memorial Chapel-Minutes, 1887-99, (Bound Volume, ) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor of the Woods Memorial Chapel-Constitution and Presidential Address, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Subseries I.2: Riverside Day Nursery
    - Annual Meetings, 1892, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Annual Meetings, 1906-12 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Annual Reports, 1889-94 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Annual Reports, 1895-99 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports, 1901-08 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Annual Reports, 1910-15 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Associate Members, [nd] (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Board of Managers: Committees-Executive, [nd] (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Board of Managers: Committees-House and Supply, c. 1900 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Board of Managers: Committees-Nursery, 1889-93, (Bound Volume, ) (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Board of Managers: Committees-Nursery, 1899-1900 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Board of Managers: Committees-Nursery, 1906-12, (Bound Volume, ) (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Board of Managers: Minutes, 1902-06, (Bound Volume, ) (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Minutes, 1905, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Board of Managers: Minutes, 1906-13, (Bound Volume, ) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Board of Managers: Minutes, 1932-43, ( Bound Volume, ) (Box 4, Folder 16)
      [Also contains West 63rd Street Community House Minutes; see Box 5 Folder 17]
    - Board of Managers: Minutes--Special Meeting, June 29, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Board of Managers: Resolution, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Board of Managers: Roster, [nd] (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Board of Managers: Treasurer's Ledger, 1909-18, (Bound Volume, ) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Board of Managers: Treasurer's Ledger, 1918-30, (Bound Volume, ) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Board of Managers: Treasurer's Records, 1894-1931 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Certificate of Extension, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Certificate of Incorporation, 1889 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Constitution and By-Laws, 1899, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1896-1897, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Fundraising, ca. 1916 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - History, ca. 1897 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Mother's Meetings, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Special Events, ca. 1897, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - State Board of Charities, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - West 63rd Street Community House: Annual Reports, 1934-38 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - West 63rd Street Community House: Board Minutes, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      [See also Box 4 Folder 16]
    - West 63rd Street Community House: Constitution and By-Laws, ca. 1930s (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - West 63rd Street Community House: Correspondence, 1937-40 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - West 63rd Street Community House: Miscellaneous Records, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Subseries I.3: Child Study Association of America
    - Administrative Correspondence, Memos, and Reports, 1925-27 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Administrative Correspondence, Memos, and Reports, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Administrative Correspondence, Memos, and Reports, 1929-33 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Administrative Correspondence, Memos, and Reports, 1939-47 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Administrative Correspondence, Memos, and Reports, 1955-72 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Advisory Board, 1958-72 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Annual Meetings, 1923-52 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Annual Reports, 1895, 1925-27, 1945-50 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Art Committee, 1930-35 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Benefits and Special Events, 1924-26 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Benefits and Special Events, 1933-38, 1943-44, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Benefits and Special Events-50th Anniversary, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Benefits and Special Events-50th Anniversary-Chapter Reunions, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Benefits and Special Events-75th Anniversary, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Benefits and Special Events-75th Anniversary-Sponsoring Committee, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Benefits and Special Events-Sidonie Gruenberg-Birthday and Memorial, 1971-74 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors-Minutes and Membership Lists, 1950-72 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - By-Laws, 1940, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Certificates of Incorporation and Dissolution, 1924, 1938, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Chapter #38-Minutes, 1923-28 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Children's Book Committee, 1962-72 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Miscellaneous, 1924-25 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Conference on Parental Education, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Seminar Conferences, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Concerning Parents, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Conferences and Meetings: National Council of Parental Education, 1926-27 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Institute on Parental Education, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Miscellaneous, 1927-29 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Miscellaneous, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Miscellaneous, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Religion Series, 1931-32 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Miscellaneous, 1932-34 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Marriage and Family Social Relations, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Miscellaneous, 1935-37 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Conferences and Meetings: A Half Century of Child Study, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Miscellaneous, 1938-49 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Psychiatry: Its Contribution to Family Living, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Conferences and Meetings: National Conference on Family Life, 1947-48 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Miscellaneous, 1950-53 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Conferences and Meetings: Miscellaneous, 1962-69 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Financial Reports, 1958, 1969-72 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Goals and Purposes Questionnaire, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Sidonie Gruenberg Correspondence (A-D), 1947-49 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Sidonie Gruenberg Correspondence (E-M), 1939, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Histories, 1928-67 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Inventory of the Papers of Child Study Associationn of America Deposited in the Social Welfare History Archives of the University of Minnesota, 1974-75 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Local Chapters, 1931-32, 1948, [nd] (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - National Council of Parental Education, 1928-49 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Personnel Practices, 1965-71 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Press Releases, 1930-68 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Programs: Family Life Education, 1968-73 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Programs: Head Start, 1967-72 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Programs: Head Start-Curriculum for Parent Participation, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Programs: Montefiore-Morrisania Comprehensive Child Care Center, 1969-72 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Programs: Netherlands, 1968-73 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Programs: Nurse Training, 1963-68 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Programs: Parent Discussion Group, 1959-71 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Programs: Parent Education Groups, ca. 1971 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Programs: Peace Corps, 1967-68 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Programs: Project Enable, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Programs: Seminar Program for Public Health Educators, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Promotional Materials, 1909-13, 1926-31 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Promotional Materials, 1932-39 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Promotional Materials, 1940-49 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Promotional Materials, 1950-59 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Promotional Materials, 1963-72 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1914, 1923-25 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Publications: Program, 1918, 1923-26 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Publications: Program, 1926-31 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1926-27 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1932-35 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Publications: Program, 1934-53 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1936-37 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1940-42 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1943-44 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1945-49 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Publications: "Parents' Questions,", 1946-47 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1950-59 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Publications: Mote Pamphlet, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Publications: Newsletter, 1961-70 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Publications: Miscellaneous, 1965-70 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Publications: "Child Study Association-Past, Present and Future,", 1968-69 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Publications: "Analysis of the Publications Department of the Child Study Association,", 1970 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - R.H. Macy Company Toy Department, 1927-28 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Radio Talks, 1927-44 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Radio Talks, [nd] (ca. 1930) (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Report-"Theories and Concepts in the Practice of Parent Counseling,", 1965 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Reports-Miscellaneous, 1967-71 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Requests for Information, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Schools Committee, 1925-34 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Schools Committee, 1935-38 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Schools Committee-Reports, 1934-37 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbooks: Promotional Materials, 1895-1925 (Box 110)
    - Scrapbooks: Sidonie Gruenberg Publications, 1924-31 (Box 110)
    - Scrapbooks: Press Clippings, 1929-32 (Box 111)
    - Scrapbooks: Press Clippings, 1938-50 (Box 297)
    - Scrapbooks: Press Clippings, 1950-55 (Box 297)
    - Study Group Council-Minutes, 1926-27 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Training Course, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Training Courses, 1928-39 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Training Courses, 1943-45 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Wel-Met Merger-Correspondence, 1972-73 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Wel-Met Merger-Staff, 1971-72 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Westport-Weston Mental Health Association, 1957-60 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Subseries I.4: Friendly Aid Society
    - Annual Reports, 1898-99 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Annual Report, 1899 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Annual Reports, 1900-01 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Annual Reports, 1902-03 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports, 1904-05 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Annual Reports, 1906, 1908 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Annual Reports, 1911, 1917 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Annual Reports, 1918-19 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1920-21 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Annual Reports, 1922-23 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Annual Reports, 1925-27 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports, 1928-30 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors Correspondence, 1919-30 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors Minutes and Reports, 1919-30 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - "Bulletin,", 1900 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Certificate of Extension of Purposes, 1924 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Certificate of Incorporation, 1923 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Constitution and By-Laws, [nd], 1923 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Kindergarten Committee Minutes, 1894-1902 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Kindergarten Committee Minutes, 1902-12 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Real Estate, 1893-1930 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Subseries I.5: Goddard Neighborhood Center
    - Annual Reports, 1935-40 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1941-48 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors-Correspondence, 1951-59 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors-Minutes, 1949-53 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors-Minutes, 1955-56 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors-Minutes, 1957-59 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Brochures, 1934-58 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Budgets and Financial Statements, 1937-59 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - By-Laws, 1948-55 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Consolidation with Riverside Community House, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Foster Parents Plan, 1954-56 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Foster Parents Plan, 1957-59 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Fund Raising: Correspondence and Reports, 1934, 1947-58 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Fund Raising: Lists, 1951-58 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Fund Raising: Lists, [nd] (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Fund Raising: Lyric Theater Benefit, 1956-58 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Fund Raising: Movie Benefit, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - "Goddard Neighborhood Fact Book,", 1950 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - "Goddard Neighborhood Center: Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow,", 1948 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Program Reports, 1948-c.1955 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Real Estate, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Social Work Students, 1956-59 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Thrift Shop, 1946-56 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - United Neighborhood Houses, 1936-58 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Subseries I.6: Wel-Met Incorporated
    - Administration: Building-Correspondence, 1968-72 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Administration: Building-Financial Agreements, 1966, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Administration: By-Laws, 1956-72 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Administration: Certificate of Change of Name, 1972-73 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Administration: Community Council of Greater New York, 1965-72 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Administration: Financial Statements, 1963-66 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Administration: Financial Statements, 1968-72 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Administration: Greater New York Fund, 1965-72 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Administration: History, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Administration: Metropolitan Jewish Centers Camp Association, 1944-66 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Administration: New York State Board of Social Welfare, 1964-72 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Administration: Personnel, 1960-72 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors: Committees-Ad Hoc, 1965-69 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors: Committees-Executive, 1967-71 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors: Committees-Finance, 1968-69 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors: Committees-Lists, 1965-72 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors: Committees-Miscellaneous, 1961-69 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors: Committees-Program, 1961-62 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors: Committee Structure, 1970-72 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1943-47 (Box 25)
      [Bound Volume including supplemental reports and correspondence]
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1948-51 (Box 25)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1952-56 (Box 26)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1957-60 (Box 26)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1960-62 (Box 27)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1963-64 (Box 27)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1961, 1966, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1972-73 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors: Rosters, 1969-70 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Camp: Advertisements, [nd] (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Camp: Conference Center, 1970-73 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Camp: Counsellor Training Program, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Camp: Narrowsburg, 1972, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Camp: Promotional Material, 1962, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Camp: Reports, 1956-72, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Camp: Scholarship Fund, 1967-73 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Camp: Silver Lake, 1948-72 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Camp: Vacation for the Aging, 1965-72 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Camp: Valeria Home, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Real Estate, 1929-83 (Box 1)
  - Subseries I.7: Riverside Community House
    - Anniversaries, 1947, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Annual Meetings, 1947-54 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Annual Meeting, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Annual Reports, 1939-57 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Benefits, 1952-54 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors: Advisory Board, 1939-45 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors: Committees-Executive, 1951-58 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors: Committees-Miscellaneous, 1941-58 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors: "Data for Board of Directors,", ca. 1940s (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1940-43 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1944-45, 1947-49 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1950-53 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1954-56 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Board of Directors: President's Records, 1945-58 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors: Resignations, 1940-52 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors: Rosters, 1940-51, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors: Secretary's Reports, 1939-47 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Brochures, 1945-50s (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Certificate of Change of Name, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Certificate of Change of Purposes, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Certificate of Extension of Existence, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Certificate of Incorporation, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Certificate in Increase in Number of Directors, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Certificate of Report of Existence, 1951 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Charter, 1944 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Constitution and By-Laws, 1940-58 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Ethical Culture Play School, 1948-50 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Executive Director Correspondence, 1948-58 (Box 31, Folder 15)